THARUNIKA A

Production Executive

9042063639



tharunikaashokan@gmail.com



Bengaluru, Karnataka



SUMMARY

Highly motivated and professional Executive with over 3 years of experience in the Bio-pharmaceutical Industry providing high-level support to senior executives. Seeking for a job opportunity to enhance and explore my knowledge and technical skills which will help for the betterment of my future and for the development of the organization.

EDUCATION

SRI RAMAKRISHNA COLLEGE OF ARTS AND SCIENCE FOR WOMEN

Master's Degree in Microbiology (2018 - 2020)

SRI KRISHNA ARTS AND SCIENCE COLLEGE

Bachelor's Degree in Microbiology (2015 – 2018)

SKILLS

- Strong organizational and timemanagement skills
- Exceptional communication and interpersonal skills
- Ability to work independently and as part of a team
- Detail-oriented and able to handle multiple tasks simultaneously
- SCADA and HMI operation
- Experience in handling process equipment and troubleshooting

AREAS OF INTEREST

- · Bio nanotechnology
- Quality Control
- Pharmaceutical Manufacturing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Production Executive

Biocon Biologics | Sep 2022 - Jul 2023

- Working experience in Clean Room Facility techniques and procedures
- Ensure process operations with compliance to cGMP, cGLP, and other regulatory requirements and maintain 5S on the Shopfloor
- Preparation and transfer of Media, Feeds, Buffer and Solutions to Bioreactor for manufacturing of biosimilars (Trastuzumab and Bevazicumab)
- Performs calibration and verification of analytical instruments based on the requirements
- Training and guiding junior team members

Production Trainee

Pasteur Institute of India, Coonoor | Jun 2020 - Jun 2022

- Worked as an Intern in the Production department (Tetanus Vaccine)
- Trained in Seed Revival and Sub-culture of Clostridium tetani for Tetanus toxin production and preparation of Production medium
- Operates automatic and manual process equipment of varying complexity with accordance with standard operating procedures
- Performs machine setup, equipment cleaning and daily checks to support the Manufacturing operation

INTERNSHIP

Project Student

Centre for Bio-science And Nano-science Research (CBNR) \mid DEC 2019 - MAR 2020

• Exploration of Zinc oxide (ZnO) Sodium Alginate Hydrogel Nanocomposite Bandages for Wound Pathogen

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Working experience in cGMP Procedures and cGLP practices.
- Handling of Documents like Checklists, SOPs, Change control, Deviation, BMR, and BPR with GDP practices.
- Doing integrity checks for the filters to ensure proper usage of the filters.
- Performs CIP and SIP processes for the cleaning purpose of process equipment.
- Handling of Single-use mixers (SUM), Media, and Buffer Preparation Tanks (500L, 2kL and 6kL).
- Hands-on experience with analytical instruments like pH and Conductivity meter (Mettler Toledo), Osmometer (Osmo Tech), UV Spectrophotometer (CECIL), and Filter integrity tester machine (Millipore).
- Operating and Maintaining Process equipment namely Freeze Dryer, Tabletop centrifuge (Thermo Scientific), Production Fermentor (400L), Autoclave, and DHS.
- Sample collection and processing for Centrifugation, pH checking, Staining techniques (Gram's staining), and Microscopic Examination as per SOP.
- Planning and execution of Preventive maintenance activity as per planned schedules for improving the overall reliability and safety of plant equipment and machinery.
- Coordinates the Validation activity and Performance Qualification process for sterilizing equipment.

PERSONAL DETAILS

• Name: Tharunika A

Date of Birth: 09/03/1998Father's Name: Ashokan K

• Gender: Female

• Address: 4/9A, Gajalakshmi nagar, Sathyanarayanapuram, Chinthamanipudur, Coimbatore - 641103.

• Nationality: Indian

• Languages Known: Tamil, English (Read, Write, Speak)

DECLARATION

Place: Bengaluru	Yours Faithfully,
Date:	THARUNIKA A

I hereby declare that the information contained herein is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.